時代華納
威 秀 電 影
拉 特 帕 克
沙 丘 娛 樂
幾個世紀以來人類和巫師和平共處
黑暗巫師莫德雷德的出現打破了這種平靜
人類成為了他邪惡野心的受害者
他正在向卡美洛進軍 那是人類的最後一座要塞
卡美洛
烏瑟 我看這場仗我們贏不了
Uther, I don't think we can win this fight.
我瞭解莫德雷德 投降的話他會接受
I know Mordred. He would accept surrender.
拿著王冠
Hold the crown.
給我拿穩了
And hold it steady.
衝啊 幹掉他們
Drink their blood!
殺
War!
大家別忘了 莫德雷德崛起前
Let us not forget that before Mordred,
巫師和我們普通人和平共處
the Mages lived among us in harmony.
我們和巫師之間的關係一直都非常友好
Our relationship with them was always peaceful.
那時候他們沒嘗到力量的滋味 也沒造出那群戰爭怪物
That was before they tasted power, and produced those creatures of war.
但錯的只是莫德雷德 跟巫師無關
But it was only Mordred, not his people.
所以為什麼要屠殺他們 沃蒂根？
So why are we slaughtering them, Vortigern?
殿下你以前不是和巫師關係很好嗎？
Was not the Prince friendly with the Mages at one time?
還跟莫德雷德學習過
Did he not study with Mordred himself?
你想說什麼？
What are you implying?
是我父親送我跟他學習的 作為雙方友好的象徵
I was sent to study with him by my father as a token of diplomacy.
我們只是想提醒尊敬的國王陛下
We would only seek to remind Your Majesty
正是一位巫師 梅林把聖劍交給您的
that it was a Mage, Merlin, who gave you the great sword.
點火
Light!
沒有梅林和那些巫師 我們今天能坐在這嗎？
Where would we be without Merlin and the Mages who helped him?
那他們在哪？為什麼現在還不出現？
Where are they now? Why do they not show themselves?
您知道他們在那 麥西亞大人
You know where they are, Lord Mercia.
- 他們正忙著逃命呢 - 夠了
- They are running for their lives! - Enough!
放箭
Loose!
現在開始 我們停止殺戮
There will be no more killings.
也不准再追殺巫師 聽明白了嗎 弟弟？
There will be no more purges. Am I clear, brother?
都下去吧
Now leave me.
和平？
Peace?
暫時而已
For a while.
我們過來是不是打擾你們兩交流感情？
Have we arrived in time to save you from each other?
但是我只想跟你交流感情
The only person I need saving from is you.
我是看孩子的 不是你
I came for the child, not you.
除非你能搶得過我
Then you'll have to fight me for him.
我弟弟今天不太舒服
My brother's not himself today.
好好照顧他
Look after him.
我們明天見
I'll see you tomorrow.
都準備好了嗎
Are the men ready?
準備好了
Yes, they are.
您確定要這麼做嗎 大人？
Are you sure about this, my Lord?
聽我說 寶貝 我現在要你按我說的做
Listen to me, woman. I need you to do as I tell you.
出什麼事了？
What's going on?
我要你帶著亞瑟離開這裡
I need to get you and the boy away from here.
事後我會盡快追上你們
And I'll join you as soon as I can.
烏瑟 我好怕
I'm scared, Uther.
我有聖劍 快點
I have the sword. Hurry.
你怎麼知道這個地方？
How do you know of this place, my love?
告訴我 我們要去哪？
You must tell me where we're going.
為什麼不回答我？
Why do you not answer me?
告訴我來這幹什麼
Tell me what we're doing down here.
華 納 兄 弟 娛 樂 公 司
出  品
親愛的 到底怎麼回事
My darling, tell me what it is.
威 秀 電 影 有 限 公 司
聯 合 出 品
告訴我怎麼了 我會幫你的
Tell me what it is, and I'll make it stop.
沒事的
It's okay.
拉 特 帕 克 - 沙 丘 娛 樂
聯 合 出 品
荒 路 影 業
安 全 屋 影 業
制  作
蓋·裡奇/威格拉姆
作   品
蓋·裡奇
作 品
解開小艇
Untie the skiff.
亞 瑟 王
鬥獸
爭
霸
查理·漢納姆
阿斯特麗德·伯格斯-弗瑞斯貝
傑曼·翰蘇
艾丹·吉倫
米卡埃爾·佩斯布蘭特
裘德·洛
艾瑞克·巴納
倫底紐姆（今倫敦）
安娜貝拉·沃麗絲
彼得·費迪南多
金斯利·本-阿德
尼爾·馬斯克爾
導 演
蓋·裡奇
吾王萬歲
King Vortigern!
閃開
Move!
嘿
Hey!
站住
Come here!
來吧 來吧
Come on! Come on!
快跑 兒子
Run, son!
國王陛下駕到
Step aside for the king.
讓他們回去幹活
Get them back to work.
遵命
Sire.
隊長 讓你的人老實點
Sergeant! Get them under manners!
您還是這麼英俊 陛下
Still so handsome, my king.
水位為什麼下降？
Why has the water dropped?
還有聖劍為什麼現在就現身了
Why does the sword reveal itself now?
塔還沒建成 我現在還沒準備好
I'm not ready, the tower is not complete.
因為您的力量增強 反抗您的力量也在增強
As your power increases, so, too, do the forces that will oppose you.
保持平衡是不可違背的定律
Balance is a law that cannot be transgressed.
真正的國王終會來臨
The born king will come.
這件事不可避免
It is inevitable.
我們說好的
We had a deal.
我獻祭摯愛之人 讓鮮血流入水中
When the blood of a loved one is spilt in these waters,
而你們要滿足我的願望
my desire must be met.
我們的約定說的很清楚 國王
There is no ambiguity, my Lord.
我們也從未有過一絲違背
We kept our side of the covenant.
是你弄丟了那個男孩 還有聖劍
It was you who lost the boy, and the sword.
那我犧牲的還不夠多嗎？
Have I not sacrificed enough?
難道你沒有感覺到力量的增長嗎？
And have you not felt your power increase?
你每征服一個王國 你的高塔就會再高一層
With every kingdom conquered, with every level added to your tower.
當您用高盧的銀子建造塔頂
When it is capped with the silver from Gaul,
你就能得到你想要的
you will have what you wanted.
找到男孩
Find the boy.
殺啦他
Kill him.
聖劍就會只聽從你的召喚
And the sword will answer only to you.
如果你想要更多幫助
If you desire further help,
你是知道代價的
you know the price.
早上碰到了那群維京人
Bumped into the Vikings this morning.
他們非要我給你這個 並且
They insisted I give you this
致以罪真誠的歉意
with their deepest apologies.
早點好起來
Get yourself well.
這不是你的責任 亞瑟
This wasn't your responsibility, Arthur.
別犯傻了
Don't be silly.
你跟姑娘們照看我的時間 比我照看你們的時間長的多
You girls have looked after me for a lot longer than I've looked after you.
我欠你太多了
I owe you everything.
你笑什麼？
What's so funny?
我只想知道你怎麼讓維京人出錢的
I just wanna know how you get money out of Vikings.
直接問他們要
You ask them for it.
- 開門  - 嘿
- Open the door! - Hey.
我們奉國王之命
Open in the name of the king!
開門吧
Open it.
有何貴幹？
Yes, gentlemen?
有個叛徒往這來了 挨家搜查
A turner come down this way. We're searching all houses.
慢點 新來的 免得出什麼簍子
Whoa. Slow down, new boy, before you trip up.
你說什麼？
What did you say?
這雙手不想要了
I'm gonna take your hands for that.
隊長
Sergeant!
這地方我之前怎麼給你說來著？
What did I tell you about this establishment?
他先碰我的 大人
He touched me, sir.
你應該覺得自己走運
Well, you should count yourself lucky.
別人想碰他還得花錢呢
Most people have to pay for that.
現在帶著你的狗 馬上出去
Now take your terriers and get out!
傑克眼
Jack's Eye.
他們來這裡幹什麼？
What did he want in here?
反抗份子最近又有動靜了
Resistance are on the move again.
攻擊了上游的一艘駁船
Hit a branding barge upriver.
有你們不認識的人來嗎？
Anyone in the house you don't know?
這我不確定 傑克 這裡人來人往的
Well, I'm not sure, Jack. People come and go.
但我們不會沾上他們
But we don't fall that side.
好吧 也許把
Ah, well, that's as may be.
誰知道誰會沾上
Well, they fall where they fall.
「真正的國王」這種鬼話對大家都沒有好處
This "born king" bollocks isn't good for anyone.
介意我看看嗎？
Mind if I take a look?
他在流血
He's bleeding.
逃跑的時候中箭了
Took an arrow on the way out.
攻擊國王的船 那個人被抓住後 會怎麼樣？
What would happen to a man who hits the king's barge upriver?
你知道會怎麼樣
Well, you know what would happen.
那可有的罪受了
And it doesn't happen quickly.
那要有人窩藏這個人 又會怎麼樣？
What would happen to the people harboring such a man?
那就跟那個人受一樣的罪
Well, they get treated the same as the man they hide.
是這樣的
Would they, now?
那我們就不歡迎你來這了 兄弟
Not sure you're too welcome here, mate.
他們會好好招呼你的 兄弟 你不用擔心
You're in safe hands now, no need to worry.
我們去屋裡談 立刻
In the back room, now.
這麼回事傑克 跟我們有什麼關係？
What's this all about, Jack? What's it got to do with us?
你知道那個人是誰嗎？
Do you have any idea who that man is?
我猜他應該很有名 可惜我不知道
For a man who's so popular, I'm surprised I don't.
「老泥鰍」比爾
Goosefat Bill.
我知道這個人 你們幾次
I know who he is. He got that moniker
把他扔進監獄 都逃了 所以有了這個綽號
'cause he keeps slipping out from the bars you keep putting him behind.
今晚在你們這找到他 對你們可不太好
He was found in this establishment, and that doesn't look good for you.
怎麼回事？
What's going on?
什麼怎麼回事？
What's going on where?
現在有人在注意你 亞瑟 經常提到你的名字
You've got some heat on you, Arthur. Your name keeps coming up.
哪些人提到的？
In what circles?
我隔壁的大媽提到的
My mum's sewing circle.
我可是個黑甲兵隊長 你說我聽誰提到的？
I'm a Blackleg sergeant, stupid. What circles do you think?
跟我說一下那個叫露西的女孩
Now, tell me a story about a girl called Lucy,
叫"灰鬍子"的維京人
a Viking called Greybeard,
還有在牆上塗的那些反動字眼
and some rebel graffiti dirtying these walls.
你是要寫書嗎？
Are you writing a book?
告訴我 說清楚點
Tell me. Every detail.
我們跟幾個維京人稍稍聊了幾句
We had a quiet word with a couple of Vikings.
退後 退後
Get back! Back!
從頭開始跟我說 從一開頭說
I said from the beginning, the very beginning.
我早上起床
I woke up.
然後呢？
Then?
然後我穿上衣服
Well, then I got dressed.
走下樓 看到姑娘們 露西不見了
I went downstairs, I saw the girls. Lucy was missing.
露西呢？
Where's Lucy?
- 她是個好姑娘- 人很好
- She's a good girl. - A nice girl.
- 她在這工作 - 然後
- She works here. - Then?
然後 我們幾個打理一份生意
Then me and the lads took care of a bit of business.
處理了一些事
Bit of housekeeping.
一切都正常嗎？
Everything as it should be?
從那些船上弄來的戰利品
That's the spoil from the boats.
- 然後呢 - 然後聽說
- Then? - Then we heard...
喬治昨晚又有麻煩了
George had trouble again last night.
好吧 我們出去見面
All right, meet me out the front.
哪個喬治 喬治國王 憤怒的喬治？
Which George? King George? Angry George?
屠龍喬治 說清楚點 亞瑟
George of the Dragon? Be clear, Arthur.
- 哪個喬治？- 我們的喬治
- Which George? - Our George.
中國人喬治 功夫喬治
Chinese George, Kung-Fu George.
- 喬治 - 亞瑟
- George? - Art.
- 我們有麻煩了 被那幫- 維京人
- We heard he'd had some trouble with the... - Vikings.
好吧 他們都不太好說話
Well, none of them are house-trained.
- 我以為你警告過他們了 - 警告了
- I thought you'd warned them. - I did.
他們的英語說得不好
They don't speak English good.
我看至少比你說得好
They speak it better than you.
等等 往前一點
Hold up, hold up. Back up.
你確定見到喬治之前沒見到過別的人嗎？
Are you sure you didn't see someone else before you saw George?
亞瑟 早
Morning, Art.
還有麥克
We saw Mike.
早 麥克
All right, Mike.
煎餅麥克 油條麥克 那個麥克？
Mike the Spike? Kosher Mike? Which Mike?
你簡直說得我頭暈
You're giving me a headache.
扁鼻子麥克
Flat-Nose Mike.
那傢伙在我們的地盤販賣毛皮 還不給我們回扣
He was trafficking furs through our vicinity without paying a commission.
今兒的貨不少啊 比平常多的多
That's quite a load, bit bigger than usual.
是啊 突然都到了 只好都裝上車
Yeah, changed last minute. Just landed on me.
多了總比少了好
More is better than less.
多了啥時候都比少了好 麥克
More is always better than less, Mike.
多了絕對比少了好 麥克 賺的錢多
More's definitely better than less, Mike. You've had a result.
對不起 亞瑟 以後不會了 我保證
I'm sorry, Art. It won't happen again. I promise.
沒關係 麥克
You're all right, Mike.
能交朋友 何必樹敵呢
Why have enemies when you can have friends?
- 你把錢放哪了？- 什麼錢？
- Where'd you put the money? - What money?
- 錢嗎？- 什麼錢？
- Money? - What money?
你把錢和寶貝藏起來了
Did you hide it with the rest of your coffers?
你到底想問什麼 一會問這個一會問那個
You're all over the place. You can't keep your questions in a straight line.
我想原原本本的說 但你一直打斷我
I'm trying to tell a story here and you keep interrupting.
再說了 我根本沒什麼寶貝
Anyway, I don't have any coffers.
除了給你的那份
Once you've taken your share,
我還得養著這幫老弱病殘 根本沒閒錢
and I've looked after the weak and needy, I'm left broke.
麥克和皮毛
Mike and the furs.
總算能說正事了 是嗎傑克
So we're back to that story, are we now, Jack?
- 你幹什麼 麥克- 分享收穫
- What are you doing, Mike? - Sharing the wealth.
錢別遞給我 麥克 規矩不是這樣的
Don't pass it to me, Mike. It doesn't work like that.
把它給濕棍子
Give it to Wet Stick.
我是貝克·萊克 你給我幹什麼？
I'm Back Lack. What are you giving it to me for?
我弄錯了
What was I thinking?
別煩我們老大 麥克 他可是不收錢
Don't upset the boss, Mike. He doesn't handle the money.
對比起 今天我忙暈了
Sorry, it's been a long day.
這才剛開始呢
It's first thing in the morning, Mike.
- 他付錢了？ - 他當然付了
- Did he pay? - 'Course he paid.
那個麥克是個好人
He's a good boy, that Mike.
花點零錢 學學街頭規矩才對
Buy some lessons in street etiquette with the change.
- 零錢？- 我們不找零 麥克
- Change? - There's no change, Mike.
- 再見 麥克 - 再見 麥克
- See you later, Mike. - Cheers, Mike!
到底怎麼回事 傑克？
What is this about, Jack?
反動圖畫 小男孩
Rebel graffiti. A young boy.
你們這的 名叫布魯
Your boy. Blue Boy.
他是個好孩子
And he's a good boy.
嘿 你們幹什麼呢
Oi! What are you lot doing?
我說你們千萬不要找錯人了 傑克
Don't start getting the wrong end of the stick, Jack.
他是個模範市民
He's an upstanding citizen.
你最好管管你們家的小東西 萊克
I think I found something that belongs to you, Lack.
你幹什麼？ 小子
What you doing, boy?
他回來了
He's coming back.
你說誰回來了？
Who's coming back?
「真正的國王」
The born king.
對 等他們來了 你屁股就開花了
Yeah, and when he does, he'll spank your arse.
給我把手洗乾淨 趁你這雙手還在
Now, let's get your hands clean while you still got some.
他們會砍掉你的手 把你關起來
He'll cut 'em off and have you in chains.
如果我們能抓住你 他們也能
If we can catch you, they can catch you.
如果你能抓住他 我們也能
If you can catch him, so can we.
我們還是接著說喬治和那幫
Should we go back to George, and the trouble with the...
- 維京人 - 出什麼事了？
- Vikings. - So what happened?
那幫人開始耍威風 然後露西就倒大霉了
Started throwing their weight about, and then Lucy got the worst of it.
- 你再說一遍？ - 他們傷了露西
- Come again, George? - They hurt Lucy.
- 我們的露西？- 這樣可不行 傑克
- My Lucy? - That can't happen, Jack.
這樣絕對不行 傑克
That can never happen, Jack.
聽著 她是我的朋友
You see, she's a friend of mine.
所以你必須補償她一下
So you're gonna have to sort her out.
警告了他們 必須付錢
They'd been warned. They had to pay.
你怎麼讓維京人出錢的？
How'd you get money from a Viking?
這問題不是個笑話嗎
I feel a joke coming on here.
當然問他要了
You ask him for it.
你先付錢 然後就能走
You're paying and then you're leaving.
這小子問我們要錢？
This Guy ask us for money?
沒人和你說話 小寶貝
Nobody's talking to you, sweetheart.
好好坐在那別說話 你最適合這個
You sit there and be quiet. You are better at that...
不然我就一箭射穿你的腿
Or I'll have to put an arrow through your lard-loving thigh.
你沒帶武器直接走過去 問他們要錢嗎？
You were unarmed. You just walked in there and asked them for it?
沒錯 傑克 他們也給我了
That's right, Jack, and they gave it to me.
他們都披著皮毛 就是
They were trying on furs. The same furs, as it happens,
扁鼻子麥克想瞞著我們販賣的皮毛
that Flat-Nose Mike tried to hide from us.
多了啥時候都比少了好 麥克
More is always better than less, Mike.
"灰鬍子"朝我們吼了幾聲
Old Greybeard banged on for a bit.
我有五十個經驗豐富的戰士
I got 50 seasoned men of war.
你想見識一下 我們維京人的刀鋒嗎
You could shave a pig on the edge of our blades.
你沒帶武器的話 插他喉嚨的那把刀哪來的？
If you were unarmed, where'd you find the blade to put to his throat?
好吧 貝克·萊克射穿了那個傻大個的豬大腿
Well, I borrowed it from his big, silly mate
我就從他身上拿了把刀
after Back Lack put an arrow through his lard-loving thigh.
退後
Get back!
就這麼回事 傑克
That's your story, Jack.
我這走
I am leaving.
但我要帶著一年的工錢走
But I'm leaving with a year's wages.
"灰鬍子"放下了自己的尊嚴
Old Greybeard surrendered his dignity.
露西拿到了一年的工錢
Lucy got a year's worth of wages.
而牆上的反動圖畫也都沒了
And the rebel graffiti exists no more
因為被風趣幽默的布魯和他風趣幽默的老爸給擦掉了
because of the law-abiding, proactive Blue Boy and his fun-loving dad.
再然後呢 他們就過上了幸福的生活
And then, they all lived happily ever after.
不 他們幸福不了
No, they didn't, Arthur.
因為這一次 有件事你恐怕不知道
Because for the first time, there's something you don't know.
也沒人告訴你這件事
Something nobody told you.
什麼事？
And that is?
那幫維京人受國王庇護
They're under the protection of the king.
一旦你惹上國王庇護的人 我就幫不了你
And once you're under the protection of the king, I can't help you.
誰都幫不了
Nobody can.
他們不會來抓我的
They're not gonna bother about me.
情況怎麼樣？麥西亞
Where do we stand, Mercia?
就剩最後一批年齡合適的人了
We're down to the last men of the right age,
但是仍然沒人能拔出聖劍
and still no one has pulled the sword.
現在就把鳥放回鳥籠吧 卡蒂亞
Now put the bird back in the aviary, Catia.
最近一段日子 民眾都不太安分
There's a general restlessness among the people.
事故更多了 反動圖畫也更多了
More incidents. More graffiti.
請您原諒 國王陛下
I beg your pardon, Your Majesty.
- 如果我… - 過來吧
- If I'd known... - Come here.
說說你的意見
I want your opinion.
麥琪可以代表民眾
Maggie represents the people.
她來自英格蘭一個古老的家族
She's from one of the oldest families in England.
她能告訴我們
She can tell us.
遵命
Sire.
民眾們敬愛我嗎？
Do the people love me?
我敬愛陛下您
I love Your Majesty,
如果我能代表民眾 那麼
and if I represent the people, then
你就知道答案了
you have your answer. Sire.
給我們弄點吃的
Bring us something to eat.
連我都開始擔心 我們是不是做的過分了
Even I am left to wonder if we are pushing them too far.
把高塔建好
Finish the tower.
其它一切都無關緊要
Everything else will be academic.
謝謝 麥琪
Thank you, Maggie.
醒醒
Wake up!
你必須掌控它
You must control it.
醒醒 聽我說
Wake up! Listen!
你必須離開這 快點
You need to get out of here, now!
你要幹什麼 萊克？
What are you doing, Lack?
傑克眼沒有騙我們 那幫維京人不簡單
Jack's Eye was telling the truth. Those red beards are connected.
那又怎麼樣？我們也是
So, what? So are we.
不 你根本不明白
No, you don't understand.
黑甲兵要來了
The Blacklegs are coming.
等他們來了 肯定拿你殺雞儆猴
And when they get here, they're gonna make an example out of you.
你趕快走
You gotta go now.
而且不能走前門 從窗戶那And you can't use the front door. Get out the window.
他們來了 快走
They're here, move!
給我開門
Open the door!
你們兩 從後門那
Oi, you two, in the back!
把門撞開
Kick the door down!
嘿
Hey!
- 準備好了沒有 - 準備好了
- Are you ready? - Yeah, of course.
我們走吧
Here we go.
早啊 各位
All right, fellas?
早啊 小子 你一大早幹什麼呢？
Hello, boy. What are you doing out at this time?
我是個船工 大人 我要趁早潮出海
I work on the boats, sir. Out on the first tide.
船工 包裡是什麼？
The boats, eh? What's in the bag?
你年齡差不多合適
And you're about the right age.
看看你的烙印
Show us your brand.
你還沒有測試過
Have you not been tested?
我一直在海上 沒機會去測試
I'm always at sea, sir. Haven't had the chance.
那你現在又機會了
Well, that's about to change now.
放心 我會上船的 只是不是你的船
You're going on a boat, all right. Just not the one you think.
- 到了 下船  - 排成一列
- Come on then, get off! - Single file!
快點 趕快下船
Come on, get 'em off.
給你們做標記 讓他們上船
Get your brand, get your drink, then back on the barge!
往前走
Move!
走快點 往前走
Move it! Come on! Move!
往前走
Keep coming!
Move it!
他們怎麼回事？
What's all that about?
我猜這就是欠錢的下場
Guess that's what you get when you don't pay up.
孩子都被抓了
Taking the kids now.
國王把他們關在這幹什麼？
What's he got them all penned up out here for?
等你見到了國王 直接問他好了
Well, when you see the king, why don't you ask him?
走快點
Hurry up!
往前走
Move along!
感覺如何？
What was that?
天祐吾王
God save the king.
搞什麼 借過
Bollocks. Excuse me, mate.
喂
Oi.
別找事
Leave it.
不好意思 借過 抱歉
Excuse me. Behind you, pal.
抱歉 借過一下
Here, mind your back.
喂 夥計 要排隊的
Oi, pal, there's a line here.
約翰
John.
隨你便
All right, pal.
現在該我了
As you were, mate.
好了 要我幹什麼
All right, where do you want me?
特雷格 又來了一個
Trigger, I think we got one here.
過來給我唱歌
Bouncing on my knee.
你說要你幹什麼 手放劍柄上 蠢貨
Where do you think I want you? Hands on the hilt, stupid.
喂 兩隻手
Oi, both hands.
說用兩隻手
I said, both hands.
沒錯 十根手指
Right, ten digits
緊緊握住劍柄 然後猛拉
round the blunt bit. Give it a tug.
邁左腳 邁右腳
Left foot, right foot.
給來烙印
Collect your brand.
然後滾回船上去
Back on the barge.
關於他你就知道這些？
That's everything you know about him?
他的朋友都跑的很快
His people were quick to disappear.
能打聽到的就只有這些
We got what information we could.
真是哪裡都有他的身影啊
Got a lot of fingers in a lot of pies.
跟黑甲兵也搭上了關係
Blacklegs in his pockets, too.
這事我會處理
I'll deal with this.
陛下
My king...
小心點
Carefully.
你就是烏瑟的兒子
So you're Uther's son.
你不僅在陰溝裡活了下來
Not only did you survive in the gutter,
而且活得 相當滋潤
you blossomed out of manure.
陛下 您肯定找錯人了
You've got the wrong man, sire.
我是出生在一個妓院裡 倫底紐姆的一座橋下
I was born in a brothel, on a bridge in Londinium.
能拔出聖劍的 只有烏瑟·潘德拉貢
The sword can only be drawn by Uther Pendragon
和他的直系後嗣
or his direct heir.
你 感覺到了 不是嗎
You felt it, didn't you?
力量
The power.
所以你能拔出來
That's what put you out.
你只是不知道怎麼控制它
You just don't know how to control it.
我只是倫底紐姆一個妓女的私生子而已
I'm nothing but the bastard son of a prostitute.
我們倆的共同點比你以為的要多
You and I have a lot more in common than you think.
我們不僅有同樣的血統 而且還有同樣的利益
It's not just the same blood we share but also the same interests.
我們倆 都是極度渴望力量的人
We both developed a palate for power.
我從來都沒什麼力量
I've never had any power.
也從來沒有渴望什麼力量
Or any desire to achieve it.
陛下
Sire,
我可以永遠消失掉
I could simply drift away,
再也不讓你見到我
never to be seen again.
雖然我想相信你 但是你的品行讓人很難信服
As much as I'd like to believe you, your character makes that unlikely.
你昏睡的時候 我調查了你
While you were asleep, we've been busy.
我知道你是什麼樣的人
I know what kind of a man you are.
我也知道你的事
I know your story.
而且 我還見到了你的金庫
And, I've seen your coffers.
你的野心成就
Your achievements
現在就是
now stand
我要殺你的理由
as your prosecution.
如果你繼承了父親的王位
What kind of a man would you have become,
還有這個王國的所有財富
had you inherited your father's kingdom
而不是在妓院裡長大
and all its advantages
你會變成什麼樣的人？
instead of being raised in a brothel?
為什麼會生出野心？
What gave you such drive?
那你想把我怎麼樣？
So, what happens now?
你知道會怎麼樣
You know what happens now.
你很快就會成為傳奇
You're quickly becoming a legend.
有人想要見你
Someone here to see you.
誰？
Mmm-hmm.
我最好見見她
I think you need to see her.
知道我是誰嗎？
Do you know who I am?
我知道你是誰 女巫
I know who you are, Mage.
我在夢裡見過你了
I've seen you in my dreams.
梅林派你來的
You've been sent by Merlin.
那你應該知道我來幹什麼
Then you know why I am here.
所以你就是他的導師
So, you will be his guide.
而你要幫我
And you will help me.
帶他過來
Bring him here.
外面有成千上萬的民眾
There's a crowd of thousands out there.
大部分是來看你而不是看我的
They've come to see you more than they've come to see me.
我向他們展示力量
I will show them power.
向他們展示實力
I will show them strength
還有尊嚴
and dignity.
你將展示謊言 軟弱
You will show them lies, weakness,
還有恥辱
and shame.
沃蒂根國王萬歲
Hail, King Vortigern!
沃蒂根國王
King Vortigern!
他們是來看你的 但走的時候
They may have come for you, but they will leave
只會把我刻在腦海裡
and will leave with a lasting impression of me.
甚至會恨我
They may even hate me.
想恨就恨吧
I'll let them hate
只要他們害怕我
just so long as they fear.
被眾人所畏懼 發自心底的畏懼
When people fear you, I mean, really fear you,
這是
it is the most
世界上最陶醉的感覺
intoxicating sensation
無可比擬
a man can possess.
就好像有一種奇妙的力量 在你的血液中流淌
A force of something almost indescribable moves through your blood
完全主宰了你
and takes you over completely.
沃蒂根國王 沃蒂根國王 沃蒂根國王
King Vortigern! King Vortigern! King Vortigern!
我明白 你捍衛這位妓女名譽的行為
I understand that your actions were very noble,
真的是非常高尚
of defending this whore's honor.
但不幸的是 你為了這個得罪了我的維京客人
How unfortunate it was at the expense of my Viking guests.
沃蒂根國王 沃蒂根國王 沃蒂根國王 沃蒂根國王
King Vortigern! King Vortigern! King Vortigern!
看了 "真正的國王"
Behold, your born king.
看著這個撥出石中聖劍的人
Behold the man who pulled sword from stone.
你們想要預言是嗎
You wanted a prophecy.
這就是預言裡的王
This is your prophecy.
告訴我們 陛下
Now tell us, king,
你有什麼想說的嗎
what do you have to say?
等你人頭落地
When your head rolls to me,
你這個早死的傳奇 只會讓所有人
the legend you've fast become will just as quickly...
這是你的臣民
Here are your people.
更加崇敬畏懼我的名字
...add to the reverence of my name.
我為此
And for this,
向你致敬
I salute you.
不
- No! -
- 如果是國王 - 不
- If you're the king... - No!
大聲的說出來
...declare yourself.
剩下的也逃不了 除非你老老實實的上斷頭台
The rest of them will follow unless you do what needs to be done.
明白我的意思了嗎？
Do we understand each other?
如果不知道說什麼 那就讓聖劍替你說吧
If you are lost for words, then let the sword speak for you.
拿起來
Take it!
讓人們看看王者之劍的威力
And show the people the power of Excalibur.
我讓你拿起來 陛下
I said, take it, king.
舉起那把劍
Raise that sword!
看來你不行
I thought not.
這個人
This man
不會給我們的繁榮的國家帶來任何紛爭
cannot be allowed to bring discord to our flourishing nation.
他不是「真正的國王」
You're not the king!
砍了他的頭
Off with his head!
他不是「真正的國王」
You're no king!
保護陛下
Protect the king!
- Protect the king! - Come.
- 快走  - 快走
- Come on! - Move! Move!
把劍追回來 把他抓回來
Get the sword! Get after him!
快追
The sword!
快跑
Move!
快點 走
Come on. Move!
快
Come on!
跳
Now!
有人能告訴我 我們去哪嗎？
Someone gonna tell me where we're going?
不能
No.
你這麼看著我幹什麼？
So what is it you're looking at, then?
你看上我了嗎？其實我也看上你了
Are you falling for me like I'm falling for you?
我們最好小心點
We wanna be careful.
這把戲不錯
That's a neat trick.
你一定得教教我這招
You'll have to teach me how to do that.
把他放回馬背上
Put him back on his horse.
哦 你好
Oh, hello.
當你們這樣的巫師很危險 是不是？
It's quite dangerous being one of you lot, isn't it?
你會和動物溝通吧？
You're good with animals, aren't you?
你們還有專門的名字是吧？
They have a word for that, don't they?
「女巫」
"Mage."
我以為巫師都是壞蛋呢
I thought your team was outlawed.
第一次見到活生生的巫師
Never met one of you in the flesh.
我以為你們都很高
I thought you'd be taller.
而且還有鬍子
And have a beard.
你知道我蒙著頭也能看到是吧？
You do know I can see through this?
周圍都是樹
Trees everywhere.
掛起來吧
Hang that up.
別給我弄皺了
Don't want it getting creased.
那麼 就是你害「老泥鰍」比爾被抓的
So, you're the chap that turned in Goosefat Bill.
他不像你 他選錯了躲藏的地方
Unlike you, he chose the wrong place to hide.
你知道 他在黑甲兵的抓捕名單中排行第三？
You know he was the third most wanted man on the Blackleg's list?
他們一直都很想抓住比爾
They've been trying to catch him for some time.
我說過了 你的手下選錯了躲藏的地方
Like I said, your man chose the wrong place to hide.
好像是這樣
So it seems.
真想知道你怎麼逃的
I was wondering what happened to you.
我說過他們會好好招呼你
I told you, you were in safe hands.
我想說你在那幫黑甲兵中可是鼎鼎大名啊
You've made quite a celebrity of yourself among the Blackleg ranks.
你跟那幫國王的衛兵 關係處的
You've done very nicely on the back of your cozy relationship.
可不是一般的好啊
with your kingsmen.
還早就不是人人指著鼻子罵的小孩子了
You know, I'm a little old for finger-wagging and speeches.
除非你是我的親爹 這個應該不可能
So, unless you're my dad, which, I believe, is unlikely,
所以你能不能老實的告訴我 你們到底想要什麼呢？
can you just get around to telling me exactly what it is you want?
應該是你想要什麼
What is it that you want?
我想離開這個地方 看看我的生活裡還剩下什麼事什麼人
I want to get my arse out of here and see what's left of my life and the people in it.
但你不會讓我這麼做的 是嗎？
But you're not gonna let me do that, are you?
我為什麼不會？
And why aren't we?
你死了兩個手下
You just lost two men.
但是為了救我 你甚至不惜犧牲五個手下
But you were prepared to lose five to save this pretty neck.
- 我認識你嗎？- 現在認識了
- Do I know you? - You will in a minute.
手伸出來
Put your hands out.
我刻不伸 夥計
I don't think so, mate.
所以我那都去不了 對嗎？
So I'm not going anywhere, am I?
那你到底想去哪裡？
Where exactly were you thinking of going?
你已經無家可歸 妓院也被毀了
You have no more home. It was razed days ago.
以前的生活也回不去了
You've no more life to go back to.
不管喜不喜歡 事情已經這樣了
Like it or not, this is your lot.
其實我們也不喜歡你
And even we don't like you.
是不是 比爾？
Do we, Goosefat?
但讓我們感興趣的是 你可以用這把劍做什麼
But what we are interested in is what you can do with this sword.
能不能讓我單獨和他說會兒 巴哥特？
Why don't you leave him with me for a minute or two, boss?
把你的戒指戴上 親愛的
Put your ring back on, honey tits.
我怕你早上沒吃飽飯 跟我幹不了架
You haven't had enough porridge this morning to talk like that.
既然你這麼喜歡那把破劍 大人 那你就留著吧
And if you like that sword so much, Your Lordship, you can keep it
用它來削葡萄皮
to peel your grapes.
我要是沒摘下戒指 恐怕你這張臉就完了
Now that would've hurt a lot more if I left the ring on.
我懂你們的意思了
I see what you're doing.
你們想要我用那把劍 做什麼神神叨叨的事
You're trying to get me to do something razzle-dazzle with that sword.
我現在就告訴你們 我不會摻和進這種破事
I'm gonna tell you right now, I'm not gettin' drawn into this mess.
你們有一大群人
And there's an army of you.
我只有一個人
There's only one of me.
我已經幾年沒動過手了
I haven't had a fight for years.
那動嘴吧
And I'll talk.
我很喜歡動嘴
I'm happy to talk.
但你們 不要指望
But there is no way
我跟你們動手
that I am fighting.
沒招了？
Is that it?
快跑 兒子
Run, son!
拔出聖劍
pulled the sword
等著 兒子
Wait here, son.
你在抵抗聖劍的力量
You are resisting the sword.
但是聖劍沒有抵抗你
The sword isn't resisting you.
現在應該很清楚了
It should be clear by now
不管你和你的朋友 認為能從我的身上得到什麼
that whatever it is that you and your friends think you want from me,
我根本沒有
I am not it.
- 現在沒有 - 永遠沒有
- Not yet. - Not ever!
你握著聖劍的時候 看到了什麼？
What do you see when you hold the sword?
是你見到的畫面 是不是？
It is something you've seen before, isn't it?
在你碰到這把劍很久以前
Long before you ever touched the sword.
你睡得不好 對不對？
You don't sleep well, do you?
如果你能再也不做那些夢呢？
What if you could make the dreams go away?
你知道我們要怎麼做
You know what we have to do.
為了讓他能控制王者之劍 我們要帶他去黑暗之地
In order for him to control Excalibur, he needs to go to the Darklands.
不能讓他去那
That's not happening.
歡迎來到黑暗之地
Welcome to the Darklands.
那就是黑暗之地？
That's the Darklands?
那只是入口
That's the entrance.
他需要帶著聖劍去高塔
He needs to take the sword to the tower.
你必須要用聖劍觸碰到聖石
You must touch the sword to the altar stone.
別想我啊
Gonna miss me.
- 再想個辦法 - 沒有別的辦法
- Give me another way. - There's no other way.
他只能一個人去
And he has to go alone.
他一人怎麼在黑暗之地活不下去
He can't survive the Darklands alone.
- 你害怕嗎 - 我覺得我能行
- Are you scared? - I think I can manage.
你應該害怕
You should be scared.
我們來這兒有什麼破事
That's what all the fuss is about?
別著急 你很快就知道是什麼破事了
Don't worry, you'll soon understand what all the fuss is about.
他身上很多東西沒有更好 這是關鍵
You don't want all of him to survive. That's the point.
你必須徹底摧毀它現在的自我 把它打倒
You have to break his old self completely. Wear him down.
你想讓他幹大事？
You want him to think big?
那就給他個大挑戰
Give him something big to think about.
你這是在玩火 女巫
You're playing with fire, Mage.
我絕不會在他成為國王之前 就害死他
And I'm not killing the king before he's even become one.
等著 兒子
Wait here, son.
不
No!
快跑 兒子
Run, son!
該想起來的你都想起來了嗎？
Did you see everything you needed to see?
想起來了
I saw enough.
巫師之塔
The Mage Tower.
跟卡美洛那座一模一樣
It's the same as the one at Camelot.
沃蒂根把塔建的越高 他的力量就越大
The higher Vortigern builds it, the more powerful he becomes.
當高塔建成後 他就擁有莫德雷德的力量了
And when it is finished, he will have the same power of Mordred.
所以王者之劍現在才會現形
That is why the sword has revealed itself now.
哪裡有毒藥 哪裡就有解藥
Where there's poison, there's a remedy.
你們巫師都怎麼了？
What happened to your people?
他們被你叔叔殺了
They were murdered by your uncle.
就是沃蒂根挑起了戰爭
It was Vortigern who started the wars.
他妒忌你父親能當國王
He was jealous of your father's throne.
他和莫德雷德達成協議 只要他打敗你父親
So he made a deal with Mordred that they would share power
他們兩個就共享權力
once he defeated your father.
莫德雷德殺死了巫師之王
Mordred murdered the Mage King
帶著他的法杖來到了神聖之塔
and took his staff to their sacred tower,
解封了他與沃蒂根結盟的黑暗力量
where he unlocked the dark forces of their union.
但他們沒有算到王者之劍
But what they didn't account for was the sword.
梅林偷走了他的法杖
Merlin stole his staff.
隨後就鑄造了聖劍 "王者之劍"
He then forged the great sword, Excalibur,
摧毀了古老的巫師之塔
and destroyed the ancient tower.
聖劍後來被交給了湖中仙女
The sword was then passed to the Lady of the Lake,
潘德拉貢家族的血脈之族
who bound it to the Pendragon bloodline.
現在
Now,
這把聖劍是你的了
the sword is yours.
看起來他的同夥被反叛分子找到了
It seems his people have been found by the Resistance.
你手下有一萬士兵聽你指揮
You have 10,000 men under your command
職責就是維護社會秩序
for the purpose of maintaining public order.
我已經發佈懸賞通緝了
Informants have been incentivized.
- 麥西亞 - 士兵正在四處巡邏
- Mercia... - Our garrisons are patrolling the roads
挨家挨戶的搜查
and searching every town.
- 早晚會找到的 陛下 - 麥西亞
- It's only a matter of time, Your Majesty. - Mercia.
反叛份子從未構成真正的威脅
The Resistance have never posed any real threat.
麥西亞
Mercia!
你只需要幹好你自己的活
Just do your fucking job.
找到亞瑟
Find him.
比我想像的要小
Smaller than I thought it'd be.
給你了 小子
It's all yours, son.
不過他的力量特別大
I warn you, it's got quite a bite.
我們的家怎麼了？
What they done back home?
你真想知道？
You really wanna know?
說吧
Go on.
全都沒了
It's all gone.
被他們燒了
They torched the lot.
繼續往下說
I said, go on.
你應該感到榮幸
You should be flattered, mate.
連麥西亞都離開王城 去找你和這把劍
Even Mercia left the castle to look for you and that sword.
傑克出賣了我們
Jack's Eye turned.
把你的人都列了個單子給他們
Gave 'em a list of everything you valued.
他們殺了半個街區的人
They slaughtered half the neighborhood.
"淘氣"約翰也沒閒著
Mischief John got busy.
他親手燒燬了那座橋
Personally burned down the bridge.
簡直像狂歡
It was quite a party.
還要我說嗎？
Shall I continue?
其他人都怎麼樣？
What about the rest of the team?
姑娘們差不多都在
Most of the girls are with us,
家裡其他人都知道你現在的大名
but the rest of the crew pretty much got gist of your popularity
都嚇得躲起來了
and made themselves scarce.
布魯 去給我弄點喝的
Blue, go get us something to drink.
拜託老大 我也是家裡人
Come on, boss. I'm one of the crew.
布魯
Blue!
我沒事
I'm all right!
我要殺了沃蒂根
I'm gonna kill him.
這的人一直在計劃著殺他
This lot have been trying to do it for years.
聽你這麼說 肯定高興
They'd love to hear you say that.
他們等了很久 才等到一個能拔出劍的人
They've waited a long time to see a man pull this sword.
我不是為他們殺人的
I'm not doing this for them.
濕棍子
Wet Stick,
那是珀西瓦爾
meet Percival.
盧比奧 這是貝克·萊克
Rubio, meet Back Lack.
還有這位
Sir Bedivere,
就是洞穴貴族之家的大家長 貝德維爾爵士
who runs this aristocratic family of cave dwellers,
這是布魯 貝克·萊克的兒子
meet Blue, son of Back Lack.
臭名昭著的"老泥鰍"比爾
The infamous Goosefat Bill
就不用我介紹了吧
needs no introduction.
好啦
So,
你們認為能幹掉沃蒂根嗎？
you think you can take down Vortigern?
全境有12個貴族
There are 12 barons.
他們代表著英格蘭古老的家族
These represent the old families of England.
他們很快能召集一萬兩千名勇士
Between them, they can rustle up 12,000 warriors.
我們要是想成功的話
In order to stand a chance,
必須至少取到其中幾位的支持
we are going to need at least some of their support.
我可以想辦法 安排你和其中六個家族
We can arrange a meeting with six of those families...
我先打斷你一下
Let me stop you there.
可以的話
If I may,
請允許我先猜測一下 他們也許會表現出的態度
allow me to run you through the proceedings as I think they will unfold.
他們首先會告訴我們
They'll start by telling us...
如果你打算煽動民眾
If you're intending to galvanize the people of this country
反抗這個國家的現任君王 那你得有個現實的策略
against the current king, there has to be a realistic strategy.
而策略 需要領導
Strategy requires leadership.
然後 他們突然談到他們有多聰明 受過多好的教育
Then they'll bang on for a while about how clever and educated they are.
戰爭策略 外交知識 騎士精神
In the art of war, diplomacy, and chivalry.
我當領袖多不合格
And how under qualified I am.
這個人在妓院裡長大 是事實吧？
Is it not true that this man was raised in a brothel
沒接受過任何正規教育
and has no formal education of any kind?
然後就開始大加嘲諷
Then they'll start takin' the piss.
那我們要怎麼稱呼他呢？
And what are we to be called, Bedivere?
叫"妓院騎士"嗎？
"Knights of the Bordello"?
或者叫"風塵騎士"
Or "The Ladies of the Knight."
你說完了嗎？
Have you finished?
然後我針鋒相對
I'm gonna have to pull 'em on it.
你們有幽默感就好
I'm glad you've got a sense of humor.
因為你們需要這個
'Cause you're gonna need it.
然後 我不得不告訴他們
I'm gonna be forced to tell them...
一群膽小的小順羊兒
There's not a bollock between you.
這時候呢 貝德維爾
At which point, Bedivere,
你會非常生氣 出聲斥責我
you're gonna get very angry, and tell me off.
依我對你的瞭解 你會這麼說
You'll say something along the lines of, "What were you gonna do
「如果他們想打你 你打算怎麼做」
"if they wanted to fight?" And I'm gonna say,
我回答說 「我就沒想打過」
"I was never gonna fight."
然後你就會說 "那以後怎麼辦"
And you're gonna say, "Well, what was gonna happen?"
我會說 "那是你的事 貝德維爾"
And I was gonna say, "That's what you're here for, Bedivere,"
"你個愚蠢無知的老混蛋"
"you big, silly, posh bastard."
你們想讓沃蒂根自己伸出脖子 讓他去倫底紐姆？
You want Vortigern to stick his neck out and get him to Londinium?
那就得引蛇出洞
You need to tease it out.
而這根本不需要一萬兩千名勇士
You don't need 12,000 fighting men for that.
只要有我們這群人就行
What you need is this little rabble.
那好 你說我們要怎麼做？
Okay, so how's that gonna work?
如果我說的你沒聽明白 貝德維爾
If I'm moving too fast for you, Bedivere,
你隨時隨地都可以退出
you can let yourself out the side door.
你似乎很快就找到了自己的位置
You seem to have found your way very quickly.
那走吧 小子 去做晚飯吧
Now, come on, kid. You're cooking dinner.
大家好好想想 沃蒂根這傢伙最關心的是什麼
What is it that Vortigern cares about most in the world?
殺了你
Killing you.
除了這個
Apart from that.
拿到聖劍
Getting the sword.
有沒有人能開動一下腦筋
Could someone help me out here, please?
- 建成高塔 - 那我們該怎麼辦？
- Finishing his tower. - So what do we do about it?
擊沉他用來運石頭的船 封鎖航道
Sink his barges carrying his supply of stone. Block up the river.
各位 把船打穿不更容易嗎？
Chaps, wouldn't it be easier just to go through the side?
瞧 這就是沒受過教育的問題
See? That's the problem with an education.
繞都繞不開
It gets in the way.
那些運石船都是用橡木製成的
These boats are made out of seasoned oak.
堅不可摧
They're uncrackable.
所以你得打穿甲板 才能碰到龍骨
So you need to go through the deck to get to the keel.
不對 你得先打穿艙壁 才能碰到船尾
No, you need to go through the bulkhead to get to the stern.
你什麼？
What are you doing?
你在浪費時間
You're wasting your time.
我都說了 它們堅不可摧
I've told you they're uncrackable.
瞧 濕棍子 貝克·萊克
See, Wet Stick, Back Lack?
這就是教育的好處
That's what an education gets ya.
我真誠地向您致歉 國王陛下
My sincere apologies, Your Majesty.
我們的運石船沉了 反叛者封鎖了河道
The stone barges have been sunk, and they've blocked the river.
還有什麼 想想 開動腦筋
What else? Come on, more ideas.
切斷沃蒂根的奴隸供應
Interrupt his supply of slaves.
非常好 我們要怎麼做
Excellent. How are we gonna do that?
我們知道他們的運輸線路
We know their transportation routes.
哦豁 現在進入狀態了
Oof! Now we're warmin' up.
繼續開動腦筋
Come on, ideas.
燒燬他喜歡的宮殿
Burn his favorite palace down.
那要怎麼燒？
How you gonna do that, then?
我認識一位給宮廷供應白蘭地的人
I know the man that supplies brandy to the palace.
他月初送酒
Shipment first of the month.
葡萄酒還是白蘭地？
All right, Dan. Wine or brandy?
- 白蘭地 - 把門打開
- Brandy. - Open the doors.
太浪費酒了
What a waste of brandy.
如果我們不用酒的話 火能燒得這麼旺嗎
But doesn't it make the palace burn well?
一萬個男孩子 全部不到十二歲
10,000 boys. All under 12 years.
年紀夠小 容易忘記家人 只會忠誠於你們
Young enough to forget their families, and to have no other loyalty than to you.
另外 每年再給你們五千個
Plus, 5,000 more each year
只要保證我們的船 通過你們的海域
for as long as you grant us passage through your seas.
北方是我們的？
The north is ours?
這是我們的協議
That is our agreement.
有問題嗎？
Is there a problem?
我聽到一些謠言 尊敬的陛下
There are rumors, Great King.
隔著海洋的我們
Even across the seas,
都聽說了 傳說中的王者...之劍
we have heard the legend of the sword of a king
而不是您的名字
other than yourself.
我有一個問題必須要問您
I would be doing my own king a disservice
要不然的話就會損害我的國王的利益
if I did not ask this question.
您答應的協議有效嗎？
Are the boys yours to give?
你覺得你是應該相信不知所謂的謠言
Do you really consider your faith better served by a rumor?
還是不列顛島偉大的征服者
Or by the word of the conqueror of this island
而征服者的麾下還有十萬名英勇善戰的勇士
with an army of 100,000 souls behind his sword?
我絕沒有冒犯您的意思 尊敬的陛下
I meant no disrespect, Great King.
您說要見我？父親
You asked to see me, Father?
我們需要所有貴族的支持
We need the support of all the barons.
在倫底紐姆安排會面
Set a meeting in Londinium.
有六個都靠不住
For the six we doubt.
不惜一切代價 給我找到他
Whatever it takes to hunt him down.
我還是控制不了
I still can't control it.
拿起它
Pick it up.
你拿起來啊
You pick it up.
用兩隻手拿起聖劍
Pick it up with both hands.
該想起來的你都想起來了嗎？
Did you see everything you needed to see?
在哪兒
Where?
在黑暗之地
In the Darklands.
你逃避了？
Did you look away?
你想知道為什麼你任然不能控制它？
You want to know why you still can't use it.
要不你告訴我？
Why don't you tell me?
我覺得你知道答案
I think you know the answer.
等你覺得值得了就會去面對
You will face it when it's worth it to you.
別誤會了我的意思 我也逃避
Don't get me wrong, I look away.
我們都逃避
We all look away.
普通人與王者之間的區別就在這裡
But that is the difference between a man and a king.
麥琪
Maggie!
我記得我們說好了 你不會出現在這裡
I thought we agreed that you'd never come here.
你先聽她說
You need to hear this.
沃蒂根要來倫底紐姆 跟各大貴族見面
Vortigern is making a visit to Londinium to meet with the barons.
- 他會乘船過來 - 何時？
- He will travel by barge. - When?
- 三天之後 - 嗯
- Three days from now. - Hmm.
看來你的計劃奏效了
Looks like your plan worked.
一定要小心
You need to be careful.
沃蒂根的力量增強了
His power is increasing.
這棟樓沒問題 角度也很好
The building's right. The angle's right.
有三個出口可以離開城鎮
Three exits from which to leave the city.
刺殺位置俯瞰整個碼頭和大半個城鎮
A vantage point over the whole dock and most of the town.
離目標50瑪 很容易射中 還有問題嗎？
It's a 50-yard shot. I can do that easily. What's the problem?
告訴他
Tell him.
我跟你說什麼問題
Tell you what the problem is, mate.
你說樓房沒問題 但我碰巧認識那棟房子的主人
When you say the building's right, I know the man that owns that building.
那個傢伙不想任何人進去
And he's not interested in letting anyone in.
你說從屋頂刺殺國王怎麼樣？
How do you feel about a rooftop king assassination?
- 我家屋頂？-對
- My roof? - Yeah.
他至少不介意犧牲屋頂讓我們搞刺殺
And least of all the king's assassins that he'll have to hang for.
- 我會犧牲？- 有可能
- I'd hang? - Probably.
三個出口 其實只能算一個
The three exits are actually only one.
因為只要射出信號箭 兩分鐘內三個城門都會關閉
'Cause once the alarm arrow's fired, the gates will be shut within two minutes,
跑過去要六分鐘
and they're six minutes away by foot.
除非你能跑的比兔子還快 就別考慮這條路了
Unless you can run like a Neapolitan stallion, I'd forget them.
所以就剩下一個出口
So, you have one exit remaining.
是20瑪外的一家雄雞酒館
And that has a tavern 20 yards from it.
在雄雞酒館喝酒的黑甲兵
There's always more Blacklegs in the Two Hot Cocks
比街上閒逛的還要多
than there are rats on the street.
為什麼不考慮別的樓房呢 比如後面這個
Why don't you use the other building? The one back here?
因為那裡離目標有175瑪
Because it's 175 yards away.
那你能射多遠？貝克·萊克
And how far can you shoot, Back Lack?
准數瑪？ 70瑪
Accurately? 75.
比爾？
Bill?
額......75瑪
175.
跟他一樣
Same as...
不 他是說一百零七十五瑪
No, he said, "175."
好吧 老兄 你厲害
All right, mate, of course you can.
這大約有175瑪了 是不是？
That's about 175 yards, isn't it?
好了 他該發信號了
Well, he was supposed to signal.
看不到見他啊
Can't see him.
好吧 我們看不見他們
Well, we can't see them.
他們也看不見我們
And they can't see us.
嘿
Hey!
他們大概以為自己走運
Maybe they thought that was luck.
你差點殺死我們
That could've killed us.
你朋友叫得像姑娘
They scream like girls, your friends.
比爾
Bill?
目標就在衛兵前面
The wolf at the head of the pack.
老泥鰍
Goosefat,
一切都正常嗎？
everything all right?
- 老泥鰍 - 嗯
- Goosefat! - Mmm.
有什麼我應該知道的嗎？
Is there something I should know here?
他跟麥西亞有仇
Those two have a history.
不管你有什麼仇怨 我們不是來報仇的
Well, whatever it is, that's not what we're here for.
- 是吧 老泥鰍 - 嗯
- Is it, Goosefat? - Mmm.
他們已經到了
They've arrived.
麥琪 我到現在才意識到 你對我的家族有多重要
Maggie, I now realize what an important member of my household you are.
- 國王陛下… - 我還沒說完
- Your Majesty... - I haven't finished.
坐下
Sit down.
直到最近
Till recently,
只要用得好 你這顆棋子的威力有多大
I didn't recognize what a powerful tool you can be in the right hands.
我以為你是個小卒子
I thought you were simply a pawn.
但發現你扮演的角色重要的多
Turns out you're a far more significant piece.
如果我不好好利用你
And it would be witless of me
那真的是太愚蠢了
not to use that to my advantage,
說讓你這個內奸當得得心應手
given how effectively you've been used against me.
向國王致敬
Hail to the king!
國王來了
There's the king.
我覺得有點不太對勁
Something doesn't smell right.
這也太容易了
This is too easy.
慢著 慢著 慢著 別放箭
Wait. Wait, wait. Don't fire.
- 為什麼？- 事情有點不對勁
- Why not? - Something doesn't smell right.
我看所有事情都對勁的不能再對勁了
It smells as right as it's ever going to smell.
快啊 他就要到了
Come on, he's right there.
比爾 準備射箭
Bill! Get on with it!
- 這肯定是個圈套 - 他怎麼可能知道？
- It's a trap. - How would he know?
我不知道 麥琪
Don't know. Maggie.
也許他知道麥琪是我們的人了
Maybe he knows she's working for us.
我現在告訴你 那個人不是國王
I am telling you. That is not the king.
別東張西望的 往我這裡看
Stop looking around and look at me.
我是靶子 不是嗎？
I'm a target, aren't I?
我的老天 他們找了一個傻瓜來
God help us. They've sent me a buffoon.
你真是個狡猾的老混蛋 沃蒂根
You are a cunning old bastard, Vortigern.
然而你根本不明白
But what you fail to understand
你其實是在自掘墳墓 終有一天 你會遭到報應的
is that it's you who's fed the hangman that will eventually come for you.
沒錯 那不是沃蒂根
You're right, that's not Vortigern.
但至少麥西亞在
But at least Mercia's here.
老泥鰍
Goosefat.
你這是做什麼 既然是圈套怎麼還射
What have you done? You can't shoot if it's a trap!
他們不知道箭是哪射來的
They'll never know where that came from.
但是你射偏了
You missed him anyway.
我絕對不會射偏
I didn't miss anyone.
放警
Arrow!
你在幹什麼？至少不能隨意射殺別人
What are you doing? They're not targets at a fair!
那是克拉倫登 這是他活該的
That was Clarendon. He earned that.
你今天可能死不了
You might survive today.
但是死神就要來了
But the noose has been tied.
我們得趕快走 快
We need to go. Now!
我們現在就走
Now. We need to go now.
把手舉起來
Put your arms up.
你們幾個 等等 等等
Hello, boys. Wait, wait.
嘿 嘿 嘿 你們這是要去哪？站住
Hey, hey, hey. Where are you going? Stop.
隊長
Sarge!
嘿 住手
Hey! Stop!
我們走
Let's go!
- 我跟不上 你們先走 - 不行 萊克 快 我們一起走
- I'm holding you up. Go on without me. - No, Lack, come on. Let's go.
- 不 我到安全屋跟你們會合 - 我不會拋下你的
- No, I'll see you at the safe house. - I'm not leaving you!
趕快走
Just go!
他們往那了
There they are!
這邊 這邊
This way, this way.
快追
Let's go!
走 走  走
Move! Move! Move!
快走
Move!
讓開
- 讓開 - 往左走
- Get out of the way! - Left! Go left!
他們在這
Over here!
這邊
Hey. Here.
進去 這邊
In here. This way!
不能待在這
We can't stay here.
萊克呢
Where's Lack?
- 他有辦法的 - 好吧
- He's making his own way. - All right.
- 盧比奧怎麼樣？- 在流血 但死不了
- How's Rubio? - He's leaking, but he'll live.
我們得去安全屋那
We need to get to the old bathhouse.
我要是死了 就跟著他
If I go down, you follow him.
他要是死了 就跟著我
If he goes down, you follow me.
加把勁
Come on.
敵人太多了 這邊
There's too many. This way!
走
Come on!
兄弟們 快點
Come on, guys!
撐得住嗎
Can you make it?
我能撐住 沒問題
I can make it, no problem.
他們在這
Over here!
大家快追
Hey! Come on!
- 盧比奧 - 快回來
- Rubio! - Come back!
盧比奧
Rubio!
快走
Come on!
他的幫他們
They need your help.
快鎖門 喬治
Lock the door, George.
讓們從後門出去 喬治
Get the lads out the back door, George.
他們不會走的 老大
It's not gonna happen, boss.
我們都恨死黑甲討厭鬼了
They hate the Blackleg and love a fight.
他們人太多
There's too many of them.
戰鬥時他們的命 他們不會走的
It's not gonna happen. They live for this.
他們會死的 喬治
They're gonna die, George!
他們受訓就是為了戰鬥
They trained their whole lives for this.
- 放 - 放下
- Go on. - Let go. Let go.
快走
Come on! Move!
- 戰鬥 - 二隊
- Fight! - Second rank!
你們兩個下去 直接走到河邊
You two, down here. It's a straight run to the river.
你先走
You go first.
我沒時間跟你爭論 比爾
We don't have time to argue, Bill.
我們中只間有人能逃出去 有人不能
Some of us will make it out in time. Some of us won't.
要逃就一起逃
Well, better some than none!
你先走吧
You go first.
麥克 去下水道
Mike! Get down the hole.
Mike, get down the hole.
我不是老鼠
Don't like rats, boss.
戴爾
Dell.
我怕黑
Scared of the dark.
是嗎？
Really?
喬治 你勸他們走
George, will you tell them?
抱歉 老大
Sorry, boss.
舉起武器
Weapons!
你們這群蠢蛋
You silly bastards.
好好的 找死 該死
Determined to die. Shit.
聽我指揮
On my command!
我要去下水道
I'm going down the hole now.
你先請
After you.
布魯 布魯 你去哪了 小子？
Blue. Blue. Where you been, mate?
我爸爸呢
Where's my dad?
我們分開了 但他知道怎麼走
We got split up, but he knows his way.
- 我要去找到他 - 別急 布魯
- I've gotta find him. - Wait, Blue.
你爸知道自己在做什麼 他很快就會回來
Your dad knows what he's doing. He'll be back before you know it, mate.
濕棍子
Wet Stick.
布魯 布魯 布魯
Blue! Blue! Blue!
給我挨家挨戶搜查 快點
Come on, boys! Search them dwellings now!
給我進屋搜
Get through them doors!
現在要想逃出去太難了
It's not gonna be easy getting out of here now.
不能待太久 城裡沒有安全的地方
You can't stay here long. Nowhere in the city is safe.
船準備好了
The boat's ready.
貝克·萊克和布魯怎麼辦 亞瑟？
What about Back Lack and Blue, Art?
我們等到天黑
We'll wait until dark.
爸 你去哪了？
Where you been, Dad?
我先喘口氣
Catching me breath.
怎麼了？
What's wrong?
沒事 我好的很
Nothing. I'm all right.
正打算去安全屋呢
Just got to get to the safe house.
你能撐住嗎？
Can you make it?
我愛你 兒子
I love you, mate.
走吧 咱們走
Come on, let's get going.
快跑
Run!
沃蒂根下台
Down with Vortigern!
看起來你已經找到使用聖劍的辦法了
It seems as though you found a way to use the sword.
不是我控制這把劍
I wasn't controlling it.
我來
Here.
是劍在控制我
It was controlling me.
我甚至不記得發生了什麼
I can't even remember what happened.
我記得
I can.
謝謝你
Thank you.
外面有什麼事情發生
Something's happening, you know?
聽起來像是有事
Certainly sounds like it.
人們已經見識了你的力量
People have seen what you can do.
你不再是故事裡的人
You're no longer a myth.
你對於他們來說有了意義
You're starting to mean something.
我可沒有這種打算
That wasn't the intention.
他們打著你的旗號戰鬥
They are fighting in your name.
我不想擔這事
I don't wanna wear that.
是你嗎 布魯？
Is that you, Blue?
是我 老大
Yes, boss!
你找到了你老爸了嗎？
Did you find your father?
他找到了
He's found him!
我們得帶你離開這兒
We need to get you out of here.
我們趕快上船 萊克
Let's get your arse on that boat, Lack.
大霧能掩蓋我們的蹤跡
There's a good fog to cover our tracks.
走吧
Come on.
先讓喘口氣
I'll need a little breather.
去吧 等大家都上船了再來接我
Here, load everyone else up and come back for me.
不 我陪著你
No, I'll stay with you.
聽我的話 去幫大家
No, you won't. Give them a hand.
我沒事的 兒子
I'll be all right, mate.
歇一會就好了
Just give me a minute.
去吧 布魯
Come on, Blue.
你拿著這個
You carry this.
去吧 去吧
Come on. Come on.
走吧
Come on, Blue.
晚上好
Evening
抱歉 打擾了
Pardon the intrusion.
獵狗一直把我們往這引
Our dog was very keen to lead us here.
我們走
Come on.
要抓他？
Shall I pick him up, Sarge?
不 跟著他
No, follow him.
他跟蹤的那個流血的人 今天殺了我的一個人
The blood he followed was from a man who killed one of my sergeants today.
那個人之前還想刺殺我 結果卻 逃脫了 竟然想刺殺我
A man who fled the scene of an assassination attempt on me. On me, no less.
你不會碰巧知道他在哪吧？
You wouldn't happen to know where that man is, would you?
- 上船  - 我不走
I can't.
乖乖地上船 布魯 我去接你爸爸
Get in the boat, Blue. I'll get your dad.
我不能丟下他
I can't leave him!
你看看現在的情況
Have a look at this situation, would ya?
我們尊貴的英格蘭國王
The king of all England himself
竟然會屈尊來拜訪一個平民
has made the effort to visit a commoner.
一文不名的平民
A man from nowhere,
今天是我最後的日子
and today, my last day.
你看著很好
You look well,
而我可憐透了
and I feel poor.
但我更樂意成為誰呢？
But who would I rather be?
你幹什麼 小子？
What do you want, kid?
這小孩是誰？
Who's this young man?
我是清潔工
I'm the cleaner, sir.
他是你什麼人？
Who's he to you?
我不認識他
Never seen him before.
我通常晚點來 要等他們都走了 再洗盤子
I usually come in later, you know, do the dishes when they're all gone.
這是真的？
Is that the truth?
是 大人 我不會騙黑甲兵
Yes, sir. I'd never lie to a Blackleg.
好孩子
Good boy.
所以你不認識他？
So you don't know him?
不認識
No, sir.
不介意我割掉他的耳朵吧？
Then you wouldn't mind if I cut his ears off?
不是我的耳朵 你想割就割
They're not my ears. Do what you want with them.
不
No!
一直想要個兒子
Always wanted a boy.
你這個混蛋
You bastard!
給我放開他
Leave him alone!
我再問你一遍
Now I repeat,
你的同夥在哪？
where's your friend?
放開他
Let him go.
帶我兒子快走
Take the boy and...
不
No!
反叛分子格殺勿論
Crush the Resistance tonight!
弓箭手
Archers!
讓我告訴你 如果你不接受聖劍
Let me show you what your uncle will do
你親愛的沃蒂根叔叔會做什麼
if you do not accept this sword.
只有你才能阻止他
Only you can prevent this.
你必須阻止他
He must be met
用聖劍對抗高塔
where sword meets tower.
你要相信女巫
Trust the Mage.
王者之劍 拿起它
Take it.
你肯定有事情告訴我
Apparently you have something to tell me.
我猜你想知道我怎麼了
I suppose you wanna know what happened to me.
我不想逼你 但是
I don't wanna push you, but...
喬治？
George?
叛亂蔓延了
Riots are spreading.
出了倫底紐姆 蔓延到全國
Not just in Londinium. Across the whole country.
人們在為你而戰
People are fighting for you.
要說有什麼時機的話 時機到了
If there was ever a chance, it's now.
機會稍縱即逝
It's not going to last.
但是 他也說了 我們不會逼你
But, like he said, we're not going to push you.
沒問題
I'm ready.
我們去攻佔王城
We're gonna take the castle.
而且 是從前門進
And we're going in the front door.
喬治 我要你回倫底紐姆 召集大伙
George, I need you to go to Londinium, gather the lads.
女巫哪去了？
Where's the Mage?
她回山洞去了
She's back at the cave.
好吧
All right.
聽著 你剛才說我們要攻佔王城 那是什麼意思？
Now, when you say we're going to take the castle, what does that mean?
你之前不是說不會逼我嗎？
I thought you said you weren't gonna push me.
走了各位 快點 快點
Come on, lads. Chop, chop.
布魯
Blue!
- 布魯 - 你們好
- Blue! - Hello!
你們來的可真是慢啊
You took your time getting here.
我真的不想聽我妻子抱怨我
I'm not gonna hear the end of this from my wife.
今晚輪到我做飯了
It was my turn to cook tonight.
國王陛下特地派我來給各位送個口信
I've been sent by His Majesty to deliver a message.
讓我想想
Let's think...
「天黑之前來到王城」
"Be at the castle before dark"
「不然的話那個姑娘還有那個男孩」
"if you wanna see the girl and the boy"
「就完了」
"alive."
我也想留下來聊聊
I would love to stay and chat,
可是你們也確實都明白
but you do understand the situation
我和我的妻子的情況
between me and my wife.
你要敢 對我做什麼
Anything that you do to me
我們保證會 十倍奉還給他們倆
will be repaid 10 times in kind.
真是個大塊頭
Now, you're a big man.
現在你最好讓開
Now, let's see you move.
再會
Evening.
他在哪裡？
So, where is he?
他離這有一天的路
He's a day's ride from here.
只要女巫沒事他就會來
As soon as she's safe, he will come.
沒有這把劍他根本威脅不到你
He poses no threat to you without the sword.
明天
Tomorrow.
如果他不來 你應該知道發生了什麼
I don't have to remind you of what will happen if he doesn't come.
我會從小孩開頭
I'll start with the little boy.
帶著女孩給我離開
Now, take the girl and go.
這種毒液會讓你體內隱藏的力量現形
This venom will induce that which is hidden from you.
它會讓你看到 你不想看見的東西
It will show you things you do not want to see.
但是你需要它的保護
But you'll need its protection.
握住我的手
Hold my hand.
我不喜歡毒蛇
I don't like snakes.
沒有人喜歡毒蛇
No one likes snakes.
保持清醒
Stay with me.
毒液的作用會持續幾個小時
You will feel it for a few hours.
不用往前了
That's far enough.
我們盡快解決這件事好嗎？
Let's get this done quickly, shall we?
讓他跪下
Put him on his knees.
讓他給我跪下
Put him on his knees!
快 快 快
Go, go, go!
你是知道代價的
You know the price.
父親 這怎麼回事？
Father, what's happening?
出去
Leave.
父親 你臉上怎麼會有血？
Why is there blood on your face?
發生什麼事了
What's going on?
父親 你嚇到我了
Father, you're scaring me.
我真的非常愛你
I love you very much.
衝啊
Come on!
Charge!
你已經贏了
You have won,
侄子
nephew.
你 已經 贏了
You have won.
現在 陪我玩吧
Now, play with me.
看來 這把劍要屬於我了
I think that sword belongs to me now.
快跑 兒子
Run, son!
弟弟
Brother...
看來 這把劍要屬於我了
I think that sword belongs to me now.
不管你想得到什麼
Whatever price you pay,
都比不上付出的代價
it will be more than you know.
你不需要再逃跑了
You don't need to run anymore.
你再也不需要逃避了
You don't need to look away.
這把劍屬於你 兒子
The sword is yours, son.
拿起它
Take it.
你想知道 我為什麼會生出野心是嗎？
You wanted to know what gave me such drive?
因為你
It was you.
你害得我長在妓院裡
You put me in that brothel.
你把我推進深淵裡
You cut me on the streets.
我站在這裡 都是因為你
I am here now because of you.
是你
You
成就了我
created me.
而為此
And, for that,
我感謝你
I bless you.
你讓我知道什麼是魔鬼
You make sense of the devil.
上箭
Nock!
點火
Light!
準備
Ready!
放箭
Loose!
我知道這個國家的領導權
While I understand there's been a change
最近有所變更
in the leadership of this nation,
但我相信您仍然會遵守您的前任
I am confident that you will still honor the agreement
我我國君主訂下的協議
made by your predecessor and my king.
按協議規定 我們要帶一萬名年輕男子回國
We expect to leave here with 10,000 young men as agreed.
這事我不同意 夥計
Yeah, I don't think so, mate.
您說什麼？
Excuse me?
我說這事我不同意 夥計
I said, "I don't think so, mate."
我們一直想 你在幹什麼？
We've been wondering what you were doing in here.
我喜歡
I like it.
這是什麼？
What is it?
對啊 是什麼？
Yes, what is it?
旋轉木馬 還是一塊超大奶酪？
A carousel? Giant wheel of cheese?
你打算用著東西幹什麼？
What are you supposed to do with it?
我知道了
I know.
這是個舞池
It's a dance floor.
那等它完工了 我們怎麼走到中間去？
And once you finish it, how are you supposed to get to the middle?
你們把他弄進屋？
But how did you get it through the door?
是搬進來的還是滾進來的？
Did you carry it in? Or did you roll it in?
請恕我直言
May I remind you,
我國的艦隊 已經控制了海洋 包圍了不列顛島
a fleet of 3,000 longships controlling the seas, surrounding your island.
這個時候得罪我王恐怕不太明智
It would be unwise to displease my king.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
喬治 濕棍子 珀西 請跪下
George, Wet Stick, Percy, on your knees.
貝德維爾爵士 有勞你了
Sir Bedivere, if you would?
我可以多給貴國一個星期的時間
I'm prepared to extend the deadline by a week.
不行
No.
我說 抱歉了
I mean, I'm sorry.
你煩了一個錯誤
You've made a mistake.
和你們打交道的已經不是以前那個人了
You're no longer dealing with the man you previously met.
你 現在面對的是英格蘭
You are addressing England
以及英格蘭國王庇佑下的所有臣民
and all the subjects under her king's protection.
請起 喬治爵士
Arise, Sir George.
我給你們一個選擇
So you have a choice.
現在向全英格蘭臣服
You can now kneel to England...
請起 特裡斯坦爵士
Arise, Sir Tristan.
要麼我離開王座
...or I'll step off this throne,
帶著你見過的這些人 去跟你們聯絡感情
and you can deal with me as the man you previously met.
請起 珀西瓦爾爵士
Arise, Sir Percival.
我們可以看看會怎麼樣
And we can see how that goes.
威廉爵士
Sir William,
有勞你了
if you would?
我榮幸之至
It would be my honor.
好了 別跪著了
Well, now that's out the way,
吃飯吧
let's eat.
能交朋友
Why have enemies,
何必樹敵呢
when you can have friends?
請起 陛下
Arise, my king.
亞瑟王
King Arthur.
這是桌子
It's a table.
大家一起坐
You sit at it.
國王萬歲 國王萬歲
Long live the King! Long live the King!